André Marcelo Ferreira Teixeira

Residence: Rua Ruben A nº 137 8ºDrt, Porto

Mobile: +(351) 912405749 **E-mail:** marcelo.t80@gmail.com

Nationality: Portuguese Gender: Male Driving license: B/B1



Objective

Currently am Advanced Developer (Frontend / Backend) in Rocket Internet in Portugal. I am part of a team of development systems directed to the construction of Online Fashion Stores (www.emeza.de, www.emeza.de).

I intend to further deepen my knowledge giving my contribution to all the challenges posed. I find it easy to integrate me in the business environment and management capacity / organization projects.

About me

I am creative, responsible and humble. Formulate objectives and discuss my views with people around me. I have a great sense of organization and enjoy traveling to new experience a personal and professional level.

Practical sport with some regularity.

Education

Instituto Politectico do Porto – Escola Superior de Tecnologia e Gestão de Felgueiras 2008 – 2011

Degree in computer engineering

Final average: 13 valores

Escola EB 2, 3/S Celorico de Basto

Technological degree – 2004 - 2007

Final average: 18 valores

Knowledge

Programming Languages:

- Java
- Perl
- C
- C++
- C#
- PHP
- XML (DTD,XSD,XSLT)
- Python
- Haskell
- Prologue

PHP Frameworks : Zend Framework, Symfony, CodeIgniter, Yii

Java Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Struts., CXF, Java Platform, Enterprise Edition

JavaScript Frameworks: Jquery, Prototype JS, Play Framework,

Python Frameworks : Django **Google Frameworks :** GWT

Ruby Frameworks: Ruby On Rails.

Testing: PhpUnit, Junit, Cucumber, capybara.

Mobile: Objective C, Android (SDK;NDK), Windows Phone/Mobile development

Designer Patterns: Singleton, Factory, MVC; Decorator, Observer,

Operating Systems: Linux (ubuntu, debian, mint... etc), Windows, MacOSX.

Command Line: MS-DOS, Shell

IDE: Netbeans, Eclipse, Android Studio, Zend Studio, SoapUI **Version Control**: SVN, Git, Microsoft Source Save.

Servers Applicational: GlassFish, TomCat, Jboss

BPMN: Bonita Soft **Web**: Html, CSS.

Web servers: Apache 2, Ngix, Xampp, Lamp, Wamp

Database: Mysql, PostgreSQL, Access, NoSql Data bases, Couch DB, Kassandra, Oracle,

MongoDB, Hadoop, Spread, CXF, ,SQLite, SQL Server Compact Edition. **Marketing Tools:** WebTrekk, Tracking Pixel, Google Tag Manager.

Networks: Experiência no uso de SSH., HTTP, WebServices, Rest, Soap, Axis 2. OWS-2

J2EE Web Services : (JAX-WS, JAX-RS) – Soap, Rest. JavaBeans.

Professional Experience

19-03-2012 - Present - Rocket Internet Portugal

In Portugal Rocket Internet i a Web programmer.

i'm Versatile both performance functions Backend developer and frontend developer. The technologies that give more emphasis are: Zend Framework 2, PHP 5, MSQL, POSTGRES SQL, RestFul, PHPUnit, Selenium, Ruby, Capybara, Cucumber, Gerking, CSS 2 e 3, HTML 4 e 5, JS,Jquery, GIT e SVN.

I integrated projects:

Zalando: http://www.emeza.de/, http://www.emeza.ch/, http://de.kiomi.com/

http://www.fabfurnish.com/

www.officeyes.com,

03/02/2011 - 13/03/2012 . Mobile developer

During the period of transition from GLINTT to Rocket i develop various applications Mobile, more specifically for android that can be found in this url: https://market.android.com/developer?pub=andre+marcelo

Give importance to Android, and the various APIs that I used, and of course to Java.

28/11/2011 - 03/02/2012 - GLINTT - NETPEOPLE - Outsoursing BES ESI

ESI Analyst Programmer - BES.

Was responsible for building various web services using TIBCO to integrate with other applications, more specifically Java and COBOL, for this to happen, everyone had to draw and study all the necessary requirements, and develop the service based on rules.

29/12/2006 - 09/02/2012 - Programador Web

Developing Multiple Portals.

- Development of the site Tay e Diana. http://tayediana.byethost7.com/
- Development of the site Quinta da Bouça. www.quintadabouca.com(Framework Yii).
- Development of the site Pessoal. www.andremarcelo.tk/ www.andremarcelo.com
- Site Administrator Association Futsal Celorico for 2 years. (Non Remuneration) (2007-2009)
- Development of the site da AFCB Associação de Futsal de Celorico.
- Development of the site da Empresa Ferjota Construção Civil LDA.
- Development of the site da Empresa Gentil Seguros.
- Development of the site Site da Empresa CelConta.
- Development of the site Correio de Celorico.
- Development of the site Motor Basto
- Development of the site Rodabike.
- Development of the site JFdoCorgo
- Development of the site da Empresa Silva Andrade Studios.
- Development of the site do Jornal Noticias de Basto

07/06/2007 - 05/10/2007 - Net Celorico

Internship at Net Celorico during summer vacation 2007 - Function: Repair of computer systems, servers and personal computers and other equipment.

27/12/2006 - 16/07/2007 - Jornal Noticias de Basto

Web developer and Sites administrator - Trainee

Informação complementar

- I only have availability to meet the phone after 18H.
- I integrated several projects during my academic career, such as weekends participated in several workshops.
- Visit my personal website available <u>www.mteixeira.com</u>
- l Participated in projects to prevent forest fires